EYAL LILA

Full Stack Developer

SUMMARY

Experienced and passionate Full Stack Developer with a proven ability to work agilely and collaborate effectively within teams. Combining a solid scientific background in biochemical research, entrepreneurial acumen as a business owner, and analytical expertise gained from military service as an aerial imagery analyst.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Makes Innovation Hub - Internship (Israel)

April 2023 - Present

- Developed with **React** based on **Figma** designs, collaborating with product managers.
- Collaborated using Git and GitHub, following an agile methodology with Scrum sprints.
- Developed server-side with Node.js/Express, integrated with Puppeteer for scraping and Open AI API for translation.
- Created **RESTful API** endpoints and connected them to the frontend.
- Created and managed a database with MongoDB and Mongoose.
- Implemented unit tests with Mocha and Chai, managed state using Redux.

Founder and Business Owner, Eyal's Hummus (Austria)

January 2022 - December 2022

- Organized and executed B2B sales, workshops, and catering events.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with customers and suppliers.

Biochemical Research, Institute of Biochemistry, University of Innsbruck (Austria)

March 2021 - February 2022

- Conducted research on metabolic cell signaling and its impact on breast cancer.
- Accurately managed laboratory data and samples, maintaining meticulous organization.

Military Service, IDF - Intelligence 9900 (Israel)

May 2013 - May 2016

• Analyzed aerial imagery and intel to create informative visual aids for ground forces.

₿ PROJECTS

NutriScan

 $\label{eq:mernor} \mbox{MERN stack application for comparing products properties with user preferences by scanning a barcode$

- Developed React, written in TypeScript with PWA (Progressive Web App) features.
- Worked with **Node.js/Express** to develop server-side application, integrated **Puppeteer** for scraping and **Microsoft Azure API** for translation.
- Created and managed a database with MongoDB and Mongoose, managed state with Redux.
- Worked with JWT (JSON Web Tokens) and cookies for user authentication.
- Exposed **RESTful API** and connected to frontend, **deployed** both server and client side.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer, Appleseeds Bootcamp (Israel)

December 2022 - April 2023

- Completed an intensive, 5-month, 720 hours instructed and self-led learning program.
- Competence in front-end and back-end technologies, portfolio of projects with code reviews.

B.Sc. Chemistry, University of Innsbruck (Austria)

October 2016 - December 2020

Details

+43 681 84996096

☐ LilaEyal@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 16.06.1994

Links

in linkedin.com/in/eyal-lila github.com/Eyal-donut

Technologies

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, JSON, REST API, React, Node.js, Express, npm, MongoDB, Git, Vite, Webscraping, Puppeteer, JWT, PWA, Figma, Mocha, Chai, Redux, Open Al API

Languages

Hebrew – Native tongue English – Fluently speaking and writing German – Fluently speaking and writing

Citizenships

Israel, Portugal